hortonworks.com 2018-12-31

# Privacy Policy - Hortonworks

**Last updated: July 18, 2018**

Hortonworks respect your right to privacy. This privacy notice (the “Privacy Notice”) explains who we are, how we collect, share and use personal information about you, and how you can exercise your privacy rights. This Privacy Notice applies to data collected about all users of _www.hortonworks.com_ , including the Hortonworks Community Connection and other related websites, (the “Website”) and the services available on the Website (the “Services”).

The terms “Hortonworks,” “we,” “us,” “our,” and “ours” refer to Hortonworks Inc. The terms “you,” “your,” and “yours” refer to the user or viewer of the Website or user of the Services, as applicable.

Hortonworks reserves the right to make changes periodically to this Privacy Notice at our sole discretion. Changes to the Privacy Notice will be posted on this page.

If you have any questions or concerns about our use of your personal information, then please contact us using the contact details provided at the bottom of this Privacy Notice.

**Use and Purpose of Collected Information**

The personal information that we may collect about you broadly falls into the following categories:

  * __Information that you provide voluntarily__  
Certain parts of our Website may ask you to provide personal information voluntarily: for example, (1) we may ask you to provide your contact details in order for you to register for any service of Hortonworks; (2) submit requests, suggestions, or other communications to us via the Website; (3) interact with the Website or Hortonworks in general in any way that submits, releases or displays your Personal Information to Hortonworks; (4) to subscribe to marketing communications from us, and/or to submit enquiries to us; (5) access product documentation or collateral, such as white papers; or (6) register for events, such as webinars, training sessions, or summits. The personal information that you are asked to provide, and the reasons why you are asked to provide it, will be made clear to you at the point we ask you to provide your personal information.Our Website includes order forms that you fill out to request information, products, and services or to attend our conferences or events. These forms may collect your financial information, such as your banking details or credit card numbers. Hortonworks will use any financial information that you submit solely for billing and payment purposes for that particular transaction unless you grant permission for other uses. Hortonworks expressly requests that you do not provide us with any sensitive personal information (including protected health information as defined by the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (“HIPAA”)), social security numbers (unless required for payment purposes), information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or other beliefs, health, sexual orientation, criminal background, or trade union membership.
  * __Information that we collect automatically__  
When you visit our Website, we may collect certain information automatically from your device. In some countries, including countries in the European Economic Area, this information may be considered personal information under applicable data protection laws. 

Specifically, the information we collect automatically may include information like your IP address, device type, unique device identification numbers, browser-type, broad geographic location (e.g. country or city-level location) and other technical information. We may also collect information about how your device has interacted with our Website, including the pages accessed and links clicked.

Collecting this information enables us to better understand the visitors who come to our Website, where they come from, and what content on our Website is of interest to them. We use this information for our internal analytics purposes and to improve the quality and relevance of our Website to our visitors.We may also collect certain information regarding your use of the Website or the Services via Google Analytics and Marketo, including but not limited to: referring site/ad source, your activity (for example, what pages visited and for how long), IP address, browser and operating system, default language set on your computer, your geolocation (by country), and the frequency and amount of time spent in the Sandbox (as defined below). The Google privacy policy can be reviewed by you at: <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>.

Some of this information may be collected using cookies and similar tracking technology, as explained further under the heading “Cookies and similar tracking technology” below.

  * __Information that we obtain from third party sources__  
From time to time, we may receive personal information about you from third party sources (including LinkedIn, Mintigo, and third-party data brokers), but only where we have checked that these third parties either have your consent or are otherwise legally permitted or required to disclose your personal information to us. 

The types of information we collect from third parties include email addresses, names, positions, and company name, and we use the information we receive from these third parties to maintain and improve the accuracy of the records we hold about you, conduct marketing campaign, administering entry to events, and provide customer service.

In general, we will use the personal information we collect from you only for the purposes described in this Privacy Notice or for purposes that we explain to you at the time we collect your personal information. However, we may also use your personal information for other purposes that are not incompatible with the purposes we have disclosed to you (such as archiving purposes in the public interest, scientific or historical research purposes, or statistical purposes) if and where this is permitted by applicable data protection laws.

Hortonworks may use your Personal Information to:

  * we may provide your Personal Information to third parties who help facilitate the Website (for example, by providing website development, statistical analyses, data processing, or sending communications to users), but for use solely in connection with facilitating the Website;
  * we may share your Personal Information with Hortonworks’ partners for Hortonworks’ marketing and analytics purposes (we do not sell your information for commercial purposes of third parties);
  * we may provide your Personal Information to financial institutions, credit card companies, collection enterprises, and other enterprises that process payments or represent the buyer or seller to facilitate payment owed to us (such as when you register for a paid event or webinar);
  * we may provide your Personal Information to employees and contractors who owe us a duty of confidentiality in connection with a legitimate business purpose of Hortonworks;
  * we may provide your Personal Information to third parties, including, but not limited to, law enforcement agencies, state, local or federal governments, private litigants, and other companies, as may be required to (1) comply with lawful requests such as subpoenas or court orders, (2) comply with applicable state, federal, or local law, (3) prevent fraud or other illegal activities from being perpetrated through the Website, or (4) protect the property, safety, or legal rights of Hortonworks and others;
  * we may provide your Personal Information to any third party whom you have consented to receive your Personally Identifiable Information; and
  * we may provide your Personal Information to affiliated companies or business successors of Hortonworks for the same purposes as stated herein.

In addition, we may provide non-Personal Information, such as your age, interests, or the way you use the Website, to any third party for any purpose including customizing and targeting advertising messages.

**Third Parties Who May Collect Information**

The following third parties may collect information through the Website, but such information shall not include Personal Information unless you post or publish such Personal Information in areas of the Website accessible to other users or the public:

  * third parties that help facilitate the Website on behalf of Hortonworks may, from time to time, collect information through the Website in the course of providing support;
  * third parties may collect other information that you voluntarily post or publish through the Website in any way; and
  * web-crawlers such as Google or Yahoo may collect information through the Website.

The Website may contain links or references to other websites, including third party advertisers and other unaffiliated websites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies of those websites or of advertisers on the Website, and you should read the privacy policies of each website you visit. This Privacy Notice applies only to information collected through the Website.

**Legal basis for processing personal information (EEA visitors only)**

If you are a visitor from the European Economic Area, our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it.

However, we will normally collect personal information from you only where we have your consent to do so, where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you, or where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms.  In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you.

If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contact with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal information).

Similarly, if we collect and use your personal information in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are.

If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal information, please contact us at the email address set out in the section “Questions, Requests, and Concerns below.”.

**Cross Border Transfers**

The Website may be accessed from within and outside of the United States. Hortonworks controls the Website from the United States. However, we may share Personal Information and non-Personal Information for the purposes set out in this Privacy Notice with partners and third parties who are based outside of the United States. These countries may have data protection laws that are different to the laws of your country.

Specifically, our Website servers are located in the United States, and our group companies and third-party service providers and partners operate around the world.  This means that when we collect your personal information we may process it in any of these countries.

However, we have taken appropriate safeguards to require that your personal information will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Notice.

**Cookies and similar tracking technology**

We use cookies and similar tracking technology (collectively, “ **Cookies** ”) to collect and use personal information about you, including to serve interest-based advertising.  For further information about the types of Cookies we use, why, and how you can control Cookies, please see our Cookie Notice [<https://hortonworks.com/cookie-policy/>]

**Sandbox**

The “Sandbox” is Hortonworks’ self-contained virtual machine, including the Hortonworks Data Platform pre-configured to provide a personal, portable and standalone Hadoop environment.  We obtain the following information (which includes Personally Identifiable Information) when users register for Sandbox: full name, address, email, phone number, company name and role and project time frame. Additional information may be collected via Google Analytics as described above.  Hortonworks will use such information for purposes of improving the Sandbox (for example, optimizing for a particular browser or creating other language versions) and for other uses specified elsewhere in this Privacy Notice.

**Online Security**

Hortonworks supports secure online transactions using secure server technology because we want your online experience to be safe. Hortonworks will use use appropriate technical and organisational measures to protect the personal information that we collect and process about you.

**Data retention**

We retain personal information we collect from you where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a service you have requested or to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements).

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymise it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

**Children’s Data**

Hortonworks does not knowingly collect or solicit Personal Information from anyone under the age of thirteen (13). If we learn that we have inadvertently obtained Personal Information from a child under the age of thirteen (13), we will delete that information as soon as practicable. If you believe that a child under the age of thirteen (13) has submitted Personal Information in connection with the Website, please contact us at the email address set out in the section “Questions, Requests, and Concerns below.”.

**California Rights**

Once a year, users who are California residents may request from us, free of charge, certain information about the Personal Information disclosed to third parties for marketing purposes by Hortonworks (if any). Hortonworks will provide a basic report including, as applicable, the type of Personal Information that was shared and the names and addresses of all third parties who received such Personal Information in the previous calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to Privacy@hortonworks.com. Hortonworks is under no obligation to provide such reports absent a written request or more than once per calendar year.

**Your data protection rights (EEA visitors only)**

You have the following data protection rights:

  * If you wish to **access, correct, update or request deletion** of your personal information, you can do so at any time by contacting us at the email address set out in the section “Questions, Requests, and Concerns below.”
  * In addition, if you are a resident of the European Union, you can **object to processing** of your personal information, ask us to **restrict processing** of your personal information or **request portability** of your personal information. Again, you can exercise these rights by contacting us at the email address set out in the section “Questions, Requests, and Concerns below.”
  * You have the right to **opt-out of marketing communications** we send you at any time. You can exercise this right by clicking on the “unsubscribe” or “opt-out” link in the marketing e-mails we send you.  To opt-out of other forms of marketing (such as postal marketing or telemarketing), then please contact us at the email address set out in the section “Questions, Requests, and Concerns below.”
  * Similarly, if we have collected and process your personal information with your consent, then you can **withdraw your consent** at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.
  * You have the **right to complain to a data protection authority** about our collection and use of your personal information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority. (Contact details for data protection authorities in the European Economic Area, Switzerland and certain non-European countries (including the US and Canada) are available [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm).)

We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

**Your data protection rights (Argentina only)**

If you wish to access, rectify, or suppress your personal information, you can do so at any time by contacting us at the email address set out in the section “Questions, Requests, and Concerns below.” We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

**Questions, requests, and concerns**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice, please contact us at [Privacy@Hortonworks.com](mailto:Privacy@Hortonworks.com).

If you are from certain regions like Europe, you also have the right to lodge any complaints or concerns with your local data protection authority (DPA). You can find a list of the European DPAs here: <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm>

**Updates to this Privacy Notice**

We might update this Privacy Notice every now and again to reflect any changes in our privacy practices. Where the changes are material, we will inform you on our Website homepage and we will also indicate at the top of this Privacy Notice the date it was most recently updated. We encourage you to check back periodically to make sure you’re aware of the most recent version.
